Marcus Ridley

Full Stack Developer

1

321-356-3386

in <u>LinkedIn</u>



Email

Orlando, Florida



GitHub

EDUCATION

ENGINEERING IMMERSION CERTIFICATE

> Thinkful 2020 - 2021

COMPUTER SCIENCE BS

University Of Central Florida Orlando, FL 2010 - 2021

ASSOCIATES DEGREE

Computer Information Technology Valencia College Orlando, Florida 2007 - 2010

SKILLS

C.

Java

JavaScript

HTML

CSS

Node

JQuery

React

Data Structures

SQL

PostgreSQL

AWARDS

TECHNICAL CERTIFICATE
Computer Programming
Specialist with specialization in
Computer Programming
Valencia College
2012

PROFILE

Full Stack Developer, proficient in Java and JavaScript. I have four years of experience in Telecommunications and Manufacturing where I learned to work with hardware and debug software. I also have a strong affinity design and game development.

PROJECTS

Xpose Thinkful | Orlando | 2021

Xpose

- Developed a social photojournalism platform
- Built this application using PostgreSQL, Express, Node, and React

Bespoke Thinkful | Orlando | 2020

Bespoke

- Developed an application that allows users to reference cocktail recipes.
- Built this application using PostgreSQL, Express, Node, and React
- Version 2 is currently in development

Spaced Repetition Thinkful | Orlando | 2020

Spaced Repetition

- Developed an application that allows users to practice Japanese words.
- Built this application using PostgreSQL, Express, Node, and React

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Web Developer The Courtesy Bar | Orlando, FL | March 2017 - November 2020 A downtown Orlando, Florida cocktail bar.

- Led a themed weekly cocktail tasting night.
- Curated several seasonal craft cocktail menus with original recipes.
- Designed the business website and merchandise store portal using HTML and CSS.

Owner It's Just Drinks | Orlando, Florida | January 2018 - Current A downtown Orlando, Florida cocktail catering company.

- Established LLC as the Owner & Operator of Its Just Drinks.
- Deployed a mobile volume catering cocktail bar for any special event.

Cocktail Bartender Hanson's Shoe Repair | Orlando, FL | October 2016 - 2018 A downtown Orlando, Florida Speakeasy.

- Assessed customers' needs and preferences and made recommendations based on their taste.
- Curated several seasonal craft cocktail menus with original recipes.

Lab Assembly Technician Sunsight Instruments | Maitland, FL | June 2013 – April 2017 A development and manufacturing organization that produces precision antenna alignment tools, antenna monitoring systems supporting a wide variety of industries.

- Repaired and ran diagnostics on 'Returned Authorization Merchandise' equipment.
- Constructed precision antenna alignment tools in assembly line fashion.
- Analyzed and debugged firmware tests for the hardware production line.